this is nick with logosbynic.com and in
我是logosbynic.com的尼克
this lesson we'll be going over how to
这一课我们将复习如何
use markers in inkscape now markers are
在Inkscape中使用标记现在标记为
useful because they allow you to take a
很有用，因为它们允许您使用
single object and repeat it along a path
单个对象并沿路径重复该对象
without deforming the object in previous
而不使上一步中的对象变形
lessons we went over how to use pattern
我们复习了如何使用模式的课程
along path which is really useful for
沿着路径，这对
creating unique designs and patterns but
创造独特的设计和图案，但
the downside of using this tool is that
使用该工具的不利之处在于
it deforms the object as it flows along
它使对象在流动时发生变形
the path here and there's no way to turn
这条路在这里，没有办法转弯
this feature off so in order to get this
关闭此功能，以便获得此功能
result right here we need to use markers
结果就在这里，我们需要使用标记
so let's go ahead and demonstrate how to
因此，让我们继续演示如何
do this so here we are in a new document
这样做，我们在一个新的文档中
the first thing i'm going to do is
我要做的第一件事是
create the path that i'd like the object
创建我想要的对象的路径
to flow along now you can use virtually
现在你可以使用虚拟的
any path that you'd like for this
任何你想要的路径
demonstration i'm just going to use a
演示我只需要使用一个
simple circle so i'm going to grab the
简单的圆圈，所以我要抓住
circles and ellipses tool i'm going to
圆圈和椭圆工具，我要去
click and drag and hold ctrl to create a
单击并拖动并按住Ctrl以创建
nice round circle with the aspect ratio
带有纵横比的漂亮圆圈
locked like that
就像那样锁着
and the way markers work in inkscape is
而标记在Inkscape中的工作方式是
everywhere that there's a node a marker
每一个地方都有一个节点，一个标记
will be placed so what i want to do
将被放置，所以我想要做的是
first here is convert this circle to a
首先，将这个圆转换为一个
path let me go to path object to path
路径让我转到路径对象到路径
and then i'll go to the edit paths by
然后我将通过以下方式转到编辑路径
nodes tool and as you can see here we
Nodes工具，正如您在这里看到的，我们
have nodes here in these four quadrants
在这四个象限内有节点
of this shape now what i'm going to do
这个形状现在我要做的是
is i'm going to take an object and i'm
我要拿一个物体，然后我
going to convert it to a marker and i'm
我要把它转换成记号笔，然后我
going to apply the marker to this path
要将标记应用于此路径
so that there's going to be the object
所以就会有这样一个物体
at each of these four points right here
在这四个点中的每一个
so let me actually go ahead and create
因此，让我继续创建
the object now now the object that i'm
现在的对象现在就是我现在的对象
going to use for a marker is just a
要用作标记只是一个
simple star i'm going to grab the stars
简单的星星我要抓住星星
tool and i'm going to draw a star like
工具，我要画一个星星，就像
that
那
now you can use whatever shape you'd
现在你可以使用任何你想要的形状
like you can use a logo you can use an
就像您可以使用徽标一样，您可以使用
icon you can use text any vector object
图标您可以使用文本任何矢量对象
you'd like can be used as a marker so
你想要的可以被用作记号
let me turn this blue just so we have
让我把这个调成蓝色，这样我们就有了
some differentiation here
这里有一些区别
and what i'm going to do is i'm going to
我要做的是我要
convert this object to a marker now
立即将此对象转换为标记
before you convert your object to a
在将对象转换为
marker if you'd like to keep a copy of
标记，如果您想保留一份
the shape on hand i would recommend
我推荐手头的形状。
creating a duplicate copy of it because
正在创建它的副本，因为
once we convert this to a marker the
一旦我们将其转换为标记，
shape is going to disappear off of the
形状将从地球上消失
canvas so let's say you want to keep
画布所以假设你想要保留
this shape i'm going to right click this
我要右击的这个图形
and go to duplicate and i'm going to
然后去复制，我要去
take this duplicate copy and then i'll
拿着这份复印件，然后我就
go to object and i will select
转到对象，我将选择
objects to marker
要标记的对象
and now it's going to disappear off the
现在它将从地球上消失
canvas like that so let me grab this
像这样的帆布，让我拿一下
shape right here i want to apply the
就在这里，我想要应用
marker to this shape let me open up the
此形状的标记让我打开
fill and stroke menu which is located
位于的填充和描边菜单
over here or you could press ctrl shift
在这里或者你可以按Ctrl Shift键
and f on the keyboard
和键盘上的f
and i'm going to remove the fill and
我要移除填充物和
stroke fill from here so let me click
从这里填充笔划，让我点击
this red x down here to get rid of the
这个红色的x在这里去掉了
fill we don't want any fill or any
填充物我们不想要任何填充物
stroke on here we want to leave this as
在这里划一下，我们想把它留为
an invisible shape and then what i will
一个看不见的形状，然后我会做什么
do is i'll come over here to the stroke
我要做的就是到这里来冲刺
style tab now if you notice we have
如果您注意到我们有
these three input boxes right here where
这三个输入框就在这里
it says markers
上面写着记号笔
now the way this works is
现在，它的工作方式是
the ones in the front
前面的那些
the first one and the last one are the
第一个和最后一个是
first and the third this represents the
第一个和第三个表示
start point of the path and this
路径的起点和此
represents the end point of the path and
表示路径的终点，并
this represents all of the nodes
这表示所有节点
in the middle of the path that go along
在这条小路的中间
the path so to demonstrate how this
这条路径是为了展示这一点
works let me grab let me
作品让我抓住让我
click this drop down right here and i'm
点击这里的下拉列表，我就是
going to grab this star and apply that
我要抓住这颗星，然后把它
as the start node
作为开始节点
i'm going to grab this end one and i'm
我要抓住这一头，我要
going to apply this star as the end node
要将该星形应用为结束节点
there's nothing visibly changing on my
我的电脑上没有什么明显的变化
screen here because i'm using a closed
这里的屏幕是因为我使用的是关闭的
path if you're using a linear path like
路径如果您使用的是像这样的线性路径
a straight line you should see a star at
在这条直线上你应该看到一颗星星
this at the front and at the back of the
这是在前面和后面的
path like that and then i'll apply this
像这样的路径，然后我将应用这个
one to all of the nodes in the middle
一到中间的所有节点
like that and as you can see here we now
就像这样，正如你所见，我们现在
have this object going along the path
让这个物体沿着小路走
now if we want to add more objects in
现在，如果我们想要在
here we can just add new we can just add
在这里我们可以只添加新的我们可以只添加
more nodes so let me come over here to
更多的节点，所以让我来这里
the edit paths by nodes tool
按结点编辑路径工具
i'm going to click and drag over all of
我要单击并拖动所有
the nodes to select them like that and
节点来选择它们，就像这样
i'm going to click this button over here
我要点击这里的这个按钮
that says insert new nodes into selected
这表示将新节点插入到选定项中
segments
分段
and as i insert new nodes like that it's
当我像这样插入新节点时，
going to insert
要插入
more of the object as you can see here
更多的物体，你可以在这里看到
now if at any point you want to alter
现在，如果您想在任何时候更改
this you could just click on one of
您只需点击其中一个即可
these nodes and you can move it around
这些节点，您可以四处移动它
like that as you can see here
就像你在这里看到的那样
now let me go ahead and undo that
现在，让我继续解开它
because that's not the result i was
因为那不是我的结果
going for
去找
now let's say you want to alter these
现在假设您想要更改这些
markers further you want to make them
更远的标记，你想做它们
bigger or smaller or maybe even rotate
更大或更小，甚至可能旋转
them to do that what you could do is let
你能做的就是让他们去做
me first go back to the selection tool
我首先返回到选择工具
if you click on one of these drop downs
如果你点击这些下拉菜单中的一个
over here where the markers are we have
在这里，我们有记号笔
this new revamped menu as of inkscape
从Inkscape开始的这一新的改进菜单
version 1.2 with all of these neat
1.2版，包含所有这些功能
little options that we can edit if you
一些我们可以编辑的选项，如果您
click on the button that says edit on
点击显示编辑打开的按钮
canvas
帆布
you're going to get these transformation
你将会得到这些转变
handles now let me zoom in on this by
手柄现在让我可以通过
holding ctrl and rolling up the mouse
按住Ctrl键并卷起鼠标
wheel
车轮
how this works is the transformation
这是如何工作的是转变
handles that are squares allow you to
正方形的手柄允许您
distort and scale the object like that
像这样扭曲和缩放对象
so i can control the width the height
所以我可以控制宽度和高度
and i can just scale it down by holding
我只要拿着它就能缩小规模
ctrl if you want to lock lock the
Ctrl如果要锁定锁定
proportions like that you can make it
像这样的比例你可以做到的
bigger
更大
or smaller as you can see there now if
或更小，如您现在看到的，如果
you want to rotate the object all you
您想要旋转所有您的对象
have to do is click on this round node
要做的就是点击这个圆形节点
right here and allow you to rotate the
就在这里，并允许您旋转
object like that
像这样的物体
pretty simple
很简单
and if at any point you want to get back
如果你在任何时候想要回来
to this let's say you deselect it and
为此，假设您取消选择它并
you get out of here if at any point you
如果你在任何时候离开这里
want to get back to editing that all you
想要回去编辑那些你所有的东西
have to do is select the object and then
要做的就是选择对象，然后
come over here and click the drop down
到这里来，点击下拉菜单
and click on edit on canvas and you can
然后点击画布上的编辑，你就可以
edit that again like that
像这样再编辑一遍
okay so i think that should do it for
好的，我想这应该够了
this lesson actually no there's one more
这一课实际上不，还有一节课
thing i want to mention about this
关于这件事我想提一提
feature whenever you have markers on a
功能，只要您在
path they behave sort of like a stroke
路径它们的行为有点像一次划水
so over here this button right here that
所以在这里这个按钮就在这里
says when scaling objects scale the
表示在缩放对象时缩放
stroke width by the same proportion
笔划宽度按相同比例
if this if this option is disabled as it
如果此选项被禁用，则为
is on my screen that means as you scale
在我的屏幕上，这意味着当你伸缩时
this object down
这个物体掉下来了
the stars are going to say are going to
星星们会说他们会
stay the same shape
保持相同的形状
so marker that you have applied will
因此，您所应用的标记将
remain the same shape regardless of how
无论如何保持形状不变
big or small you make the path that it's
不管是大是小，你走的路是
placed along if you'd like the markers
如果你想要记号笔的话就放在一起
to scale alongside the object all you
所有人都可以沿着对象进行缩放
have to do is enable this setting right
要做的就是正确启用此设置
here and now it'll scale with it like
此时此时此刻，它将随之扩展，就像
that without changing its size
在不改变其大小的情况下
so i think that should do it for this
所以我认为这应该可以解决这个问题
lesson that is how you can go about
这就是你如何行动的教训
using markers in inkscape to repeat an
使用Inkscape中的标记重复
object along a path without deforming it
对象沿路径移动，而不使其变形
if you found this lesson useful then
如果你觉得这一课很有用，那么
maybe consider checking out my inkscape
也许可以考虑看看我的Inkscape
master class it's a collection of over
大师类，它是一个集合
60 videos where i go over all of the
60个视频，我浏览了所有
tools and features in inkscape and i
Inkscape和I中的工具和功能
explain what they are and demonstrate
解释它们是什么并演示它们
how they work kind of like how i just
它们的工作原理有点像我只是
did in this video we even have a private
在这段视频中，我们甚至有一个私人
community where you can ask questions
您可以提问的社区
and get help from me anytime you want
并随时从我这里获得帮助
i'll have some information about that in
我会在
the description below if you have any
如果您有，请参阅下面的描述
questions let me know and as always
问题让我知道，一如既往
thanks for watching
感谢收看
[Music]
[音乐]